<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-12-29T18:51:48+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><subtitle>Online Corpus delivers cyber security trainings and cyber protection software that keeps criminals away from your email.</subtitle><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Bye-bye Bulgarian cyber security</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/nation-hacked/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bye-bye Bulgarian cyber security" /><published>2019-07-23T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2019-07-23T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/nation-hacked</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/nation-hacked/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every July in Bulgaria hides its own secrets. Last year, there was a major operation against child molesters and this year… Well, this year was marked by the marvelous deeds of some people (and the lack of security built into the applications that got cracked, but more of that below).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;July was a fruitful month. Several hacking stories made the first pages in just a couple of weeks. And since I hate spreading rumors and I started hating pointing my finger at people for no particular reason, here is a short summary of what happened:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly, a ‘hacker’ from Stara Zagora published a video that was shared in the Bulgarian developers’ community (well, mainly in Facebook that is). He pointed out that he might have gotten access to the personal data of some citizens from his home town. There was also a POC GitHub repository, containing a Node application that generated valid personal identification numbers (or EGN), then the app fired those EGNs to the backend of the Stara Zagora municipality service that handled child subscriptions to kindergartens and schools. By making a crafted query, a person could be able to obtain personal data of approx 235000 people.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/hackers-have-hacked-what.jpeg&quot; class=&quot;img-thumbnail&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;355&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;The photo is taken from Petko Petkov's public facebook profile&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since pointing out the evident was basically a crime, according to the Prosecutors office, he got locked away by the local police department for 24hrs and set free after. The Prosecutors Office started working on building evidence against unknown perpetrator that ‘illegally’ (mind the quotes) gained access to personal data — a computer crime according to Article 319a of the Bulgarian Penal Code, but finally dropped the case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Next, just two weeks after the previous ‘incident’, in mid-July we had a case of an unknown perpetrator that sent and email from the Russian platform Yandex to several Bulgarian mass-medias. The email stated that the cyber security state of Bulgaria is laughable, and it contained a link to the anonymous file sharing platform, that lead to a .zip file, containing over 11GB of Bularian citizens’ personal data.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Investigators held responsive a 20-year old teenager that supposedly stole the information from several National Revenue Agency databases. Officials demanded that the stolen data was returned in one piece (they did not get the concept of ‘stealing’).
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
So, this, 20-year old ‘hacked’ his way into the database by using an SQL-injection — or at least that’s what was circulating in the media recently.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/teenager-alleged-hacker.jpeg&quot; class=&quot;img-thumbnail&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;355&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;The teenager that ‘hacks’ — according to mass media — photo from btv.bg&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Fortunately, he’s sound and safe, working from home, after a wee less than 72hrs behind bars. His personal laptops and his work laptop were seized, and later it was found out that they are encrypted. Aaaand that’s it, no harm done. The Revenue Agency stated that the data of 5 MILLION PEOPLE WAS NOT A PART OF THEIR CRITICAL INFRASTRUCTURE (well then, if the personal data of 5 million is not critical enough…). And the boy was set free. Of course, the teenager and his employer mind their own business, and refuse to share data on the case with government officials, referring to ISO 27001, stressing the fact that they hold crucially important information about their contractors and partners.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The leaked data includes personal information such as identification numbers (those EGNs we were talking about just above), names, addresses, tax and revenue data, parking tickets and penalties… Well the last two are off the list, but you get the idea. Any smart enough criminal could utilize this treasure to do damage or will try to gain something from them.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The grumpy person in me states and demands justice for all harm done! No one should go unpunished…
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Yeah, but try decrypting a LUKS partition with some random or pseudo random password. I bet it will take the police a few decades to see what truly is going on (and that is if they use a few super servers). Heck, even my Fedora needs to cool the steam when I try to unlock it unsuccessfully several times.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
We had some cyber businessmen talking about how real hackers used Linux, and that the traces left behind were from a Windows machine (well, obviously someone has not heard of VMware Workstation… 21 Century’s knocking on the door — Wakey wakey!). Leaving behind the humorous people that tend to stick their noses in places where they don’t belong is a great idea. But the ferocious public wants more. Every day numerous posts find their way to the top of the Facebook developer community list, pointing out different thought-up facts about the investigation. Well, that could prove useful for the investigators. I mean, people need a good laugh from time to time.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
So, eventually, as I see things, that teenager is going to be cleared of all charges, with a decent story to tell his children… or ladies. Either way, after a week everyone will have forgotten. Or, if the Police and prosecutors office do indeed find data regarding any illegal activity, he might face some serious jail time. Either way, time will tell.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
One thing is certain, though. Bulgarian citizens data will not be safe any time soon... Now all we need is a platform that will allow us to see just how much lateral damage we have to handle. :) I doubt that there will be any cyber-specific initiatives, having in mind the poor state of the Penal code and all the problems Bulgarian police officers suffer.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Despite all that, we keep our spirits high, quoting some random minister’s shower thoughts, shared publically: &lt;b&gt;“The data breach is not that harmful! The most important thing is to be alive and healthy!”&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Well, cheers to that!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>georgi</name></author><category term="cybercrime" /><category term="phishing" /><category term="data" /><summary type="html">Every July in Bulgaria hides its own secrets. Last year, there was a major operation against child molesters and this year… Well, this year was marked by the marvelous deeds of some people (and the lack of security built into the applications that got cracked, but more of that below).</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/cybersec-bye-bye.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/cybersec-bye-bye.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Email protector – the browser extension that keeps hackers away</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/email-protector/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Email protector – the browser extension that keeps hackers away" /><published>2019-04-25T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2019-04-25T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/email-protector</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/email-protector/">&lt;p&gt;As we’ve already mentioned and discussed &lt;a title=&quot;What is phishing&quot; href=&quot;https://onlinecorpus.com/cyber-attacks-and-cybercrime-preventing-phishing/&quot;&gt; what phishing attacks are, &lt;a title=&quot;Phishing campaigns&quot; href=&quot;https://onlinecorpus.com/everything-you-should-know-phishing-campaigns/&quot;&gt; and how are they planned in campaigns&lt;/a&gt;, how &lt;a title=&quot;Spear phishing&quot; href=&quot;https://onlinecorpus.com/spear-phishing-attacks/&quot;&gt;spear-phishing&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a title=&quot;Whaling attacks&quot; href=&quot;https://onlinecorpus.com/whaling-big-fish/&quot;&gt;whaling attacks&lt;/a&gt; rob hard-working people, just because hackers exploit the very human nature, now I want to shed some light on another problem – &lt;b&gt;until now there was no single tool that could help you and protect you while you access and use your email daily.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;Wouldn’t it be better to be more &lt;b&gt;secure&lt;/b&gt; and know whether a &lt;b&gt;message&lt;/b&gt; is coming from a &lt;b&gt;legitimate source&lt;/b&gt; or is designed to &lt;b&gt;trick you&lt;/b&gt; into opening the email and sharing your personal information or downloading a harmful file that could make your computer another node in someone else’s botnet?
&lt;b&gt;Email protector&lt;/b&gt; is a browser extension that mitigates &lt;b&gt;phishing, spear phishing and whaling attacks&lt;/b&gt;. It is designed to protect you when you do your day-to-day tasks. Instead of wasting time validating email headers by hand, Email Protector does that for you.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What is Email Protector?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Email protector is a browser extension that gets installed… on your browser. Statistics show that the most commonly used browser is Google Chrome – that is why we designed the extension to be functional with that browser. The current release supports English, German and Bulgarian languages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;What does Email Protector do?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a browser extension, you should give permission to the Protector to read the headers of the emails you receive. The extension will not touch any other line of text besides the email header. By scanning the header, Email Protector will find out if the email is coming from a legitimate source or not. If an email comes from a non-legitimate source (like the method used in this article), then the extension will inform the user about the maliciously crafted email.
But what if the email comes from a legitimate source?
Let’s say that you’re having a nice business conversation with &lt;b&gt;businessmail1@gmail.com&lt;/b&gt;. You arrange payment information, exchange invoices and payment information and all of a sudden you get an email from &lt;b&gt;businessmali1@gmail.com&lt;/b&gt; (mind the changed email name) or &lt;b&gt;businessmail@gmali.com&lt;/b&gt; (the username remains the same, but the domain is changed). This is one of hacker’s favorite methods that trick you into believing that you’ve communicating with the legitimate person or entity. You can find a detailed article about this method here.
We’ve included functionality that can protect you from those “misspelled” emails, regardless of the fact if the username or domain name was forged.
You, as the user of the Extension, can “trust” specific email addresses – the ones that you know for sure are legitimate. You can do it by highlighting an email in the Chrome browser, right-clicking it and choosing “Trust email”. The email you have trusted will be stored in the memory of the extension, and you will see the email populate the list of “trusted emails”.
The standard version of the extension includes one slot for “trusted emails”, while the premium versions include three, ten or unlimited supported “trusted emails”.
That way, if you have trusted a specific email, let’s say business@mycompany.org, and you receive other emails from users such as busniess@mycompany.org or business@mycopmany.org, you will be notified about the fact that the email senders are not the same. This notification is going to be persistent whenever you open such an email, so that you are constantly reminded of the difference in the email names and / or domains.
If you make an error adding an email, you can always remove the email from the list of trusted emails by clicking on it and then selecting “remove email” from the button below.
Additional functionality includes the proactive prevention of phishing and spam campaigns by some domains. If a domain is used for malicious purposes, we collect the email address, which is related with the spam or phishing campaign, and proactively silently inform all Email Protector clients.
Protecting yourself means protecting other as well. We take great care in not exposing any information whatsoever that could compromise anyone as an entity or an individual. That is why we do not collect any user-specific information.
Security is something that should not be compromised on. Whenever there is a malicious email that you have received, Email Protector gathers the information, such as email user name and email domain (if the email is not spoofed), to inform other Email Protector instances across the globe for the existing threat. If the email is spoofed, Email Protector creates a local cache-like blacklist. This feature is user-centric and takes user security to a whole new level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Who can benefit from email protector?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The extension is designed for day-to-day use by individuals and companies. If you’re using a browser and receiving 20+ emails daily, you’ll most probably not have enough time to go over email headers manually. That’s why we strongly recommend that you use or product. Just stay secure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Can I use Email Protector on all email platforms?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently Email Protector is limited to &lt;b&gt;abv.bg&lt;/b&gt;, &lt;b&gt;mail.bg&lt;/b&gt; and Google’s &lt;b&gt;gmail.com&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;What are the supported platforms?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a Chrome extension, currently the Email Protector could be installed on Google Chrome browsers, thus making it platform-independent (you can use it on Mac, Linux or Windows).
In the near future, we will make the Extension interoperable with Mozilla Firefox as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Where can I download Email Protector from?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find the extension in the Chrome Web Store. It’s publicly available and free for use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Is there a security training video?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currnently not, but as soon as we upload it, everything will be uploaded here for easier refference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Where can we report bugs or feature ideas?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’ve got an idea or just found a bug? You can share it with us on the corporate email! (You can see it in the footer)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>georgi</name></author><category term="email-protector" /><category term="email" /><summary type="html">As we’ve already mentioned and discussed what phishing attacks are, and how are they planned in campaigns, how spear-phishing and whaling attacks rob hard-working people, just because hackers exploit the very human nature, now I want to shed some light on another problem – until now there was no single tool that could help you and protect you while you access and use your email daily.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/email-protector-banner-hackers-away.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/email-protector-banner-hackers-away.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">What is the whaling cyber attack and how to prevent it</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/whaling-big-fish/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What is the whaling cyber attack and how to prevent it" /><published>2019-04-25T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2019-04-25T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/whaling-big-fish</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/whaling-big-fish/">&lt;h2 itemprop=&quot;articleSection&quot; class=&quot;h2-heading&quot;&gt;How do cyber criminals use whaling. What is whaling?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whaling is not only the favourite sport of the Japanese, but a type of cyberattack that uses the &lt;a title=&quot;Spear phishing&quot; href=&quot;https://onlinecorpus.com/spear-phishing-attacks/&quot;&gt;spear-phishing methods&lt;/a&gt; to go after a high-profile target. Also known as the CEO-fraud, whaling is almost the same as spear-phishing but the difference is that it uses methods such as email and website spoofing to trick the victim into performing specific actions, such as revealing sensitive data or wire transfer. Due to the evolving technologies everything becomes possible because of online communication and as &lt;i&gt;Homer Simpson&lt;/i&gt; once said “The problem with the world today is communication…too much communication.”
So on one hand &lt;a title=&quot;All you need to know about phishing&quot; href=&quot;https://onlinecorpus.com/everything-you-should-know-phishing-campaigns/&quot;&gt;phishing scams&lt;/a&gt; target random individuals and spear-phishing targets specific individuals or organizations and on the other hand whaling &lt;b&gt;goes to the next level&lt;/b&gt; by targeting the chosen victim in such a way that the fraudulent communications they send appear to have come from someone that is high ranked at their organization, such as the CEO or finance manager, or the so called “big fishes”. This type of scam requires a lot of preparation and research so to be executed successfully.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;How do whaling attacks work and how do we prevent such scams?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As mentioned above, whaling attacks need &lt;b&gt;more detailed research and careful planning&lt;/b&gt; than standard phishing and spear-phishing attacks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all perpetrators look at &lt;b&gt;social media&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;b&gt;public company information&lt;/b&gt; to establish a profile and plan of attack. For this purpose they usually use &lt;b&gt;malware&lt;/b&gt; to infiltrate the targeted network so that they can gather detailed information about the victim. To impersonate a high-value target, the cybercriminals need to take time to figure out the best way to sound like their target, find a way to approach their target, and figure out what kind of information they can get from the victims before the actual attack takes place. So when time comes the perpetrators send emails with much detail for example of a future payment in which they redirect a payment to a different bank account using the exact same writing style and invoices as the original email. So in these cases, the sender’s email address typically looks like it’s from a believable source/ CEO, business partner,senior manager etc./and may even contain corporate logos,original invoices or links to a fraudulent website that has also been designed to look legitimate. Usually A whaling attack will often use a domain name that looks very much like a trusted domain name, but with subtle and almost imperceptible changes. Because a whale’s level of trust and access within their organization tends to be high, it’s worth the time and effort for the cybercriminal to put extra effort into making the experience as casual as it can be.
Due to the rising levels of cybercrime in the recent years businesses must be aware of these kind of cyber attacks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;What measures could be taken to increase the level of security and awareness among the employees of corporations?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First of all defending against whaling attacks starts with educating key figures within your organization to ensure they are routinely on guard about the possibility of being targeted. Also encouraging key staff members to maintain a healthy level of suspicion when it comes to unsolicited contact is a must, especially when it comes to important information or financial transactions.
Employees should also be trained to look out for the telltale signs of an attack, such as spoofed (fake) email addresses and names. Simply hovering a cursor over a name in an email reveals its full address. 
By looking carefully, it’s possible to spot if it perfectly matches the company name and format. Our email protector will do the job even if you are having a bad day and you don’t have the spare time to hover stuff on the monitor around.
Senior staff members and executives should keep in mind that cybercriminals can you every bit of information they are posting and sharing online on social media sites like Facebook, Twitter and LinkedIn. Details such as &lt;b&gt;birthdays, hobbies, holidays, job titles, promotions and relationships can all be used by cybercriminals to craft more sophisticated attacks.&lt;/b&gt;
You can reduce the danger posed by spoof emails by requiring your IT department to automatically flag emails for review that come in from outside your network. Or just create a spam filter, so that messages from domains, which are not verified by Google get swept right away. But never mind that investor that just got into web design and IT stuff…
Or just you can use our Email Protector - the browser extension that will keep all kinds of phishing, spear-phishing and whaling attacks away from you.
One more thing to consider is adding another level of validation when it comes to sharing sensitive information or wiring a large amount of funds. For example, &lt;b&gt;a quick phone call may be the best practice when handling critical or sensitive tasks&lt;/b&gt;, rather than simply carrying out the transaction electronically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Things to keep in mind about whaling attacks:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A whaling attack will often use a domain name that looks very similar to the trusted domain name, but with subtle and almost imperceptible changes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You should research whether the specific domain has been bought recently OR has a newly utilized MX record — these things often times give away suspicious activity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Suspicious keywords in the body of the message, are often phrases such as “bank transfer” or “wire transfer”.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Statistics show a great progress for this kind of attack over the rest several years&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Since 2013, more than $12 billion has been unwittingly sent by 78,617 firms through the successful exploitation of CFOs and finance leaders in the U.S., UK and Europe. – A research made by Forbes magazine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The FBI reported that companies lost nearly $215 million in 2014 as a result of phishing attacks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Whaling attack instances are on the rise in the U.S., up more than 270% from January to August 2015. The FBI reports that business losses due to a whaling attack totaled more than $1.2 billion in just over two years.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In 2016, the Verizon DBIR reported 61 phishing attacks targeting finance teams. That number rose to 170 in 2017 – nearly a 200% increase!
According to cyber security provider Smarttech 247, the number of whaling attacks tripled in 2017, with companies of all sizes being targeted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>ivan</name></author><category term="whaling" /><category term="email" /><category term="data" /><category term="privacy" /><summary type="html">How do cyber criminals use whaling. What is whaling?</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/whaling.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/whaling.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">How hackers make you click on phishing emails</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/click-on-phising-emails/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How hackers make you click on phishing emails" /><published>2019-04-24T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2019-04-24T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/click-on-phising-emails</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/click-on-phising-emails/">&lt;p&gt;The noble art of hacking is all about psychology. If you leave the technical aspect aside, the one thing that gets most people is the false sense of security, overconfidence and trust. Yeah, people trust people they haven’t even seen in their life. That’s what the 21. Century is all about.
Being secure in such an insecure world seems the most absurd thing ever.
But somehow it’s all working out in the end. We are making progress and business is thriving.
Trust is what defines us as people, gives us power to overcome differences and solve almost unsolvable problems, but it can also be exploited for the most vile things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
You trust your friends, right? And if your friend uses the email address &lt;b&gt;samplefriend@example.com&lt;/b&gt;, and you are in constant connection together, you see nothing wrong in downloading an attached file, sent from &lt;b&gt;samplefreind@example.com&lt;/b&gt;, right?
Look into both emails and check if you can find something wrong.
That’s right. I’ve switched the places of two characters. I can tell you, a lot of people fell for this and clicked on the attached extension.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hackers love this. Misplacing one character in the domain name or in the username is one of the most common tactics hackers utilize to do &lt;a title=&quot;Spear phishing&quot; href=&quot;https://onlinecorpus.com/spear-phishing-attacks/&quot;&gt;spear phishing&lt;/a&gt; campaigns or whaing.
It’s a low risk, high profit strategy that, if executed correctly, gives a lot of leverage to the hackers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This kind of attack is almost uncatchable. Imagine you have an inbox full of a hundred emails per day. And you’ve got to verify every time that the email address is the correct one. That’s complete madness. A waste of time.
Our solution automates this validation. Email Protector uses several algorithms to verify the sender of the message and compare it to the email sender that you have trusted. The chrome extension is lightweight and you can download it in the chrome market FOR FREE.
Check out how out extension works!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>georgi</name></author><category term="phishing" /><category term="email" /><category term="data" /><category term="privacy" /><summary type="html">The noble art of hacking is all about psychology. If you leave the technical aspect aside, the one thing that gets most people is the false sense of security, overconfidence and trust. Yeah, people trust people they haven’t even seen in their life. That’s what the 21. Century is all about. Being secure in such an insecure world seems the most absurd thing ever. But somehow it’s all working out in the end. We are making progress and business is thriving. Trust is what defines us as people, gives us power to overcome differences and solve almost unsolvable problems, but it can also be exploited for the most vile things.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/click-on-phishing-emails.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/click-on-phishing-emails.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Phishing emails. What are the differences with real emails</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/distinguish-phishing-emails/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Phishing emails. What are the differences with real emails" /><published>2019-04-23T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2019-04-23T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/distinguish-phishing-emails</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/distinguish-phishing-emails/">&lt;p&gt;If you own a company or work for one, you know how business is organized – everything is happening via email. Meetings and discussions are just a small and harmless fraction of all emails that you receive. Well, what about invoices then? Are you aware that cyber criminals are sending fake invoices to companies and individuals? The amount of money they generate via this amazingly simple method is astonishing. If you want to learn more about this kind of cyber attack, I’d advise you to firstly read the articles about &lt;a title=&quot;Spear phishing and whaling article&quot; href=&quot;https://onlinecorpus.com/spear-phishing-attacks/&quot;&gt;spear phishing and whaling.&lt;/a&gt; They’ll give you a really nice introduction to this article.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
As you already know what a &lt;a title=&quot;Phishing attacks&quot; href=&quot;https://onlinecorpus.com/cyber-attacks-and-cybercrime-preventing-phishing/&quot;&gt;phishing attack and a &lt;a title=&quot;Phishing campaigns&quot; href=&quot;https://onlinecorpus.com/everything-you-should-know-phishing-campaigns/&quot;&gt; phishing campaign is&lt;/a&gt;, you got to know that there is nothing that can stop hackers in sending you an email.
Now the question is, how can you distinguish a harmful email from a regular one.
Since this article will be fairly technical, we’re not going to discuss the blatant and obvious give-aways of a phishing email, nor will we cover the previously discussed phishing campaigns.
As you already know what a phishing attack is, you got to know that there is nothing that can stop hackers in sending you an email.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now the question is,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;how can you distinguish a harmful email from a regular one.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since this article will be fairly technical, we’re not going to discuss the blatant and obvious give-aways of a phishing email, nor will we cover the previously discussed phishing campaigns.
If your cyber security solutions – name them antivirus products, malware blockers etc. fail to protect, the only thing that stands on the way between the cyber criminal and you, is a keyboard.
People nowadays have no accessible tool that can guarantee that the person, sending an email is the correct one. A hacker could forge the email so that it will seem as if it is sent by a legitimate institution or a person. But it’s actually not.
This tactic is often times utilized when a hacker group has taken the hold of an email account. Usually the compromised accounts are company accounts – as people pay little to no attention in following the security best practices, accounts often times get compromised and fall into the hands of hackers.
When those malicious actors have established control, they observe the correspondence between all parties. The emails hackers pay close attention to include keywords such as ‘payment’, ‘invoice’, ‘price’, ‘transaction’, ‘bank’.
After figuring out that a payment is soon to be made, hackers begin using the ‘bridge’ strategy.
As soon as the fundamental points of the strategy are complete, hackers begin either a social engineering or a spear phishing campaign against the other correspondent or they await an invoice to be received. 
Forging an invoice is really easy. That is why, one should&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Never wire a big sum of money before conducting a phone call&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When a payment has been made, and if the recipient is fraudulent, one has a limited set of actions to do in order to recover from this situation.
But let’s not talk about the worst-case scenario. It is mandatory that everyone should know what to do, but more importantly, one should know how to proactively stop a threat before it’s too-late.
How do emails work is an article that will give you enough understanding and information, so that you won’t get confused by the acronyms and technical terms in the next lines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Email servers with no spam filters - trouble for all of us&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such email servers taht lack even basic antivirus protections or spam filters fall often times victim to spammers and phishing campaign.
Usually, a mail server should block and filter messages that have to &lt;b&gt;DKIM validation&lt;/b&gt; or &lt;b&gt;SPF entries&lt;/b&gt;. In most cases, email servers that are misconfigured, do a standard SPF check, but when the SPF check fails, the email server does not block the email message. So, a malicious perpetrator gains access to the ‘Inbox’ of the unexpecting user.
Every year there are spam campaigns against the biggest free email service providers in Bulgaria – mail.bg and abv.bg. The lack of validation puts the users to a tremendous risk. Fortunately, users of Yahoo, Gmail and Microsoft Outlook are protected from emails that have no DKIM/SPF validation.
So, the attacker has gotten in the ‘Inbox’ folder of some email. His email got an attachment that will install a backdoor to an unpatched system. It’s our task to stop him do it.
Firstly, in order to verify that the email is coming from a legitimate source, and not some dubious online anonymous email service, we should check the email headers.
Email headers can’t lie to you. If the SPF or DKIM validation fails or softfails, it is surely that the sender is not a recognized source of email traffic.
The sending server might also give some information. We could check what we know about it online in just a few clicks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only when you examine an email message closely, can you fully understand what was going on when the email was sent. But verifying this information by hand every single time there is a new message in the inbox, is a tedious job.
If only there was a way to automate this check, regardless of the platform.. Well, there is! And our tool is free. You can read more about it here and download the chrome extension for free from the chrome web store.
Only then can you be sure that even if your email provider is not secure, you will minimize the risk by using the best free tools in the market.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>georgi</name></author><category term="phishing" /><category term="email" /><category term="data" /><category term="privacy" /><summary type="html">If you own a company or work for one, you know how business is organized – everything is happening via email. Meetings and discussions are just a small and harmless fraction of all emails that you receive. Well, what about invoices then? Are you aware that cyber criminals are sending fake invoices to companies and individuals? The amount of money they generate via this amazingly simple method is astonishing. If you want to learn more about this kind of cyber attack, I’d advise you to firstly read the articles about spear phishing and whaling. They’ll give you a really nice introduction to this article.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/phishing-emails-distinguish.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/phishing-emails-distinguish.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Everything you should know about phishing campaigns</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/everything-about-phishing-campaigns/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Everything you should know about phishing campaigns" /><published>2019-04-23T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2019-04-23T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/everything-about-phishing-campaigns</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/everything-about-phishing-campaigns/">&lt;p&gt;Real hackers plan every single step very carefully. What’s the trick, you’ll ask? Well, experience and common knowledge go hand in hand. And since hackers usually specialize at one area at a time, it’s really hard to know when one’s knowledge is sufficient enough and skills are technically advanced enough to conduct such an attack. Usually 95% of all spammers are just skids (script-kiddies are wannabe hackers with insuficient programming and systems knowledge). Yes, it may happen so that they catch a fish or two, but the really malicious actors are the one preparing months before a big hit.
Such a preparation has a lot of prerequites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 itemprop=&quot;articleSection&quot; class=&quot;h2-heading&quot;&gt;So how do hackers plan and execute campaigns?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
Bore continuing on, have you checked out the article that goes about &lt;a title=&quot;Cyber attacks and cybercrime: Preventing phishing&quot; href=&quot;https://onlinecorpus.com/cyber-attacks-and-cybercrime-preventing-phishing/&quot;&gt;what phishing is and how to prevent it?&lt;/a&gt; Check it out if you have not.
We’re not going to dive into some old cases of mine, as the technical details are overwhelming and this blogpost will be even hardly readable. I’d rather shed a light on what the Internet folks do.
To be fair, there is a gazillion ways to launch a campaign - and often times it occurs as spontaneous as it sounds. Of course, the results of such a campaign will be close to zero and the - withough previous planning a campaign such as this will be a total failure.
The &lt;b&gt;fruit bearing&lt;/b&gt; way that hackers often times adhere to, is to launch a campaign whenever they have gained enough data like names, emails, phone numbers. But that’s all random data - a phishing campaign is nothing more than collecting some data or even buying it and then using it for malicious purposes. During those campaigns, mailcious actors have no real idea who they will compromise. That’s the main difference with wailing or spear phishing.
So, whenever a phishing campaign is launched, it has the following goal:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;b&gt;Gain access to target sensitive information&lt;/b&gt; - A campaign often times start with a mass mail-spam. The messages aim to trick the user into revealing important data — often a username and password that the attacker can use to breach a system or account. The classic version of this scam involves sending out an email tailored to look like a message from a major bank; by spamming out the message to millions of people, the attackers ensure that at least some of the recipients will be customers of that bank. The victim clicks on a link in the message and is taken to a malicious site designed to resemble the bank's webpage, and then hopefully enters their username and password. The attacker can now access the victim's account.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Download a malicious payload&lt;/b&gt; - This is a bit tricky for cyber criminals nowadays, as most email apps and big corporations – Yahoo, Google, Microsoft have their own security solutions that can protect users from harmful campaigns. Those messages almost always end up in spam or get deleted – depending on the user’s settings. That’s why malicious users target middle-sized and small companies that usually have some IT staff that manages the email server. Often times those email servers are neglected – even an update is a lux that the IT guys can’t afford to have. As you’ve probably guessed, most of those companies use open-source software that is reliable, but if left not updated could cause serious damage to the company.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leaving the admin stuff to the side, when a user gets a new message guess what happens? The user opens the email message – correct. Now, if the user sees that there is an attached file, he does what? Correct once more, he clicks and downloads the attached file. My personal observation shows that more than 80% of all users that have been infected and/or scammed have clicked and downloaded  an attached file.
If the user, runs a Windows OS instance on his laptop or tower, the chances that a malicious actor could gain access to the user’s system skyrocket. Don’t get me wrong – the Windows 10 team has repaired some of their Office Macro critical flaws that enabled macro execution and could carry some really harmful powershell functions, that in a flick of the command prompt could turn your computer into another hacked node – part of a botnet. It’s just wee bit difficult to make a Linux or a Mac user execute a file with root permission.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To sum it up – I’ve always advised people to think first. If you receive an email address from an ‘official institution’ - whether it would be the IRS, your Email provider or someone from your company, make sure that the message you’re getting has the correct sender – if not, you are being a target of a phishing campaign. And remember – official institutions always, ALWAYS send a paper copy of the documents to your physical mail.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>georgi</name></author><category term="phishing" /><category term="campaign" /><category term="data" /><category term="privacy" /><summary type="html">Real hackers plan every single step very carefully. What’s the trick, you’ll ask? Well, experience and common knowledge go hand in hand. And since hackers usually specialize at one area at a time, it’s really hard to know when one’s knowledge is sufficient enough and skills are technically advanced enough to conduct such an attack. Usually 95% of all spammers are just skids (script-kiddies are wannabe hackers with insuficient programming and systems knowledge). Yes, it may happen so that they catch a fish or two, but the really malicious actors are the one preparing months before a big hit. Such a preparation has a lot of prerequites.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/phishing-campaign-criminal.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/phishing-campaign-criminal.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">What are spear phishing cyber attacks and how are they used</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/spear-phishing-attacks/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What are spear phishing cyber attacks and how are they used" /><published>2019-04-23T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2019-04-23T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/spear-phishing-attacks</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/spear-phishing-attacks/">&lt;p&gt;One of the most common methods cybercriminals use is the so called phishing – a cyber attack that is focused on getting access to one’s computer system, its passwords, also credit card data, bank accounts or other sensitive corporate information that could bring them easy money. To get this information cyber criminals are using email, social media, and any form of communication they can to gain access of and steal valuable data. You can find more about the broader term &lt;i&gt;phishing&lt;/i&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;What do we need to know about phishing&quot; href=&quot;https://onlinecorpus.com/cyber-attacks-and-cybercrime-preventing-phishing/&quot;&gt;in our previous article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
One specific type of cyber attack used by criminals is the spear-phishing. The target of the spear phishing attack is a specific individual or business. This attack is achieved by acquiring personal details on the victim such as their, hometown, employer, locations they frequently visit, and any other online activity they have, or in the other case, information about the business activity, payment methods, style of communication and business associates. The main goal is to deceive the target into clicking or downloading a malware, or into initiating an undesired action such as a wire transfer. Spear-phishing attacks are designed in such a way that the messages are modified to specifically address the victim, assuming that it comes from an entity that they are familiar with and containing specific, detailed personal information. Spear-phishing requires more research and time than phishing. The perpetrators try to obtain as much personal information about their victims as possible to make the emails they send look legitimate thus increasing their chance of fooling recipients. Because of the personal data that is included in the emails, spear-phishing attacks are more difficult to identify than phishing attacks (due to the broader range of the basic phishing attack).This is the reason why spear-phishing attacks are becoming more widespread.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;How does spear phishing work&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Businesses are most vulnerable to spear-phishing attacks because most of their company data is public and freely available online. This makes the job of the hacker of getting the information needed to perform a phishing attack a piece of cake. The official website of a company and all the other social networks that it is connected to like facebook, linkedin, twitter are full with detailed information about the activity of the company, its ceos, managers employers, customers etc. In a spear-phishing email, these details available online can help the perpetrators to write their email in such a way that it would deceive the recipient enough to convince him to click the malicious link . Once the malware is downloaded the hackers are ready to capture sensitive internal-only data, thus allowing them to have free access to the corporate network and steal intellectual property, corporate data or even worse to easily redirect a payment to a criminal bank account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;So how do we prevent a spear-phishing attack?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knowing how to protect ourselves online is something that is becoming more and more important nowadays. We share personal information even more than we know or want. In an evolving world full of technology every company is obligated to ensure that its employees are well prepared against cyberattacks.
&lt;b&gt;Rule Number One&lt;/b&gt; is never to click open emails from senders you don’t know. While working, we get the habit to click and open every single email that we receive, but this is exactly what criminals are waiting for. This is the reason most of the scams succeed. When you receive a deceiving email you don’t even pay attention to the small details that are changed, like misspelled domain names and typos in the email name. This is costing businesses around the world millions of dollars.
Worldwide, thre is not one signle solution that manages this kind of attack. Well, fortunately for all of us, we’ve created a &lt;b&gt;free&lt;/b&gt; tool that can handle this troublesome situation. Our Chrome extension makes business email communication much more reliable and secure.
&lt;b&gt;Education&lt;/b&gt; is another important factor.Every company must educate its employees about the different types of cyberattacks and what to pay attention to when exchanging business emails. Senior management, key staff, and financial teams MUST be educated about the effects of spear-phishing and whaling attacks and how to spot them. These employees must be trained to spot the common characteristics of phishing attacks like spoofed senders, unrequested attachments, or spoofed hyperlinks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other key factor is practise.  Employees must regularly be put through fake whaling attacks to test their knowledge and awareness. These small steps will improve significantly the safety of the business process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For additional online security you must adhere to these simple steps:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take a few more seconds to create stronger passwords&lt;/li&gt; 
&lt;li&gt;Change passwords regularly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enable a two-step verification (2SV) or two-factor authentication (2FA)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Perform regular scans on user and infrastructure systems for malware and keep the software up to date&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you receive an email with changed details (bank accounts, phone numbers, location, addresses, recipients etc.) &lt;b&gt;always double check and personally contact the sender to confirm the changes&lt;/b&gt; - this means that you’ve got to put your fear of speaking with someone on the phone away, pick up the phone and make a simple call.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal of the attackers is to make employees neglect the changes. Almost always emails like these contain the obvious sence of urgency - urgent reply, an urgent transaction or a specific urgent instruction that one should do.
In this way the employee has no time to react and think over the changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a hard thing keeping yourself safe. I’ll allow myself to rephrase Bruce Lee by saying that we should take great attention in the words one is using in his day-to-day communication with others. Stay sharp and don’t let yourself be trciked.
&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>ivan</name></author><category term="cybercrime" /><category term="phishing" /><category term="data" /><summary type="html">One of the most common methods cybercriminals use is the so called phishing – a cyber attack that is focused on getting access to one’s computer system, its passwords, also credit card data, bank accounts or other sensitive corporate information that could bring them easy money. To get this information cyber criminals are using email, social media, and any form of communication they can to gain access of and steal valuable data. You can find more about the broader term phishingin our previous article</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/spear-phishing-drawing.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/spear-phishing-drawing.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Cyber attacks and cybercrime: Preventing phishing</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/preventing-phishing/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cyber attacks and cybercrime: Preventing phishing" /><published>2019-04-22T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2019-04-22T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/preventing-phishing</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/preventing-phishing/">&lt;p&gt;Phishing is without doubt the most commonly used and most preferred way to infiltrate any system. Perhaps you’ve heard of the phrase &lt;i&gt;“You give a poor man a fish, and you feed him for a day, you teach him to phish, you give him… you give him…”&lt;/i&gt; – well the whole world actually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 itemprop=&quot;articleSection&quot; class=&quot;h2-heading&quot;&gt;Phishing can't be classified as a real cyber crime, right?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s not quite accurate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Phishing is a type of cyber attack, that uses the weakest link in Internet – the human. Phishing is the most successful social engineering attack to extract user data – login credentials, user names, passwords, email addresses, as well as payment data and other valuable information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
The term ‘phishing’ shows that attackers do not aim to gather information from one specific individual, but rather rely on the fact that data will be collected regardless of the victim, unlike whaling, spear phishing or business email compromise attacks.Phishing could be utilized with different methods and means – targets are contacted by email, telephone or text message by someone posing as a legitimate institution to lure individuals into providing sensitive data. The information could then be used to access different accounts or further continue with data extraction.Since almost everybody reacts negatively to cold calls, cyber criminals utilize email as their primary tool and most conventional way to execute this kind of attack.Another method is the creation of web-pages and domains that look exactly like the original ones – with one major difference – they’re operated by a malicious individual or a cyber crime gang.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;&lt;b&gt;COMMON FEATURES OF PHISHING&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Unknown recipient&lt;/b&gt; – almost always phishing emails begin with ‘Dear customer’, ‘Dear client’ or use a ‘general’ way to address the recipient.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Too Good To Be True&lt;/b&gt; - Lucrative offers and eye-catching or attention-grabbing statements are designed to attract people’s attention immediately. For instance, many claim that you have won an iPhone, a car, or some other lavish prize. The most important thing to do is not to click on hyperlinks in this email (or better – delete the email before even reading it).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Sense of Urgency&lt;/b&gt; – One way that cybercriminals exploit your normal human behavior is that they create a situation, in which you should act only in a limited time frame. Some emails will say that you have only hours to respond – a good example for that are email messages from senders, pretending to be your email provider or other linked third party. Those messages contain the statement that your email account will be suspended, if you do not activate it – the email will provide a button and after you click a whole bunch of bad stuff could happen. When in doubt, one should check the headers of the message – does the real sender correspond with the email sender? Checking headers can often times be troublesome and time consuming. This article gives you the answers what to look for when examining header information.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Hyperlinks&lt;/b&gt; - A phishy hyperlink can often times be hard to catch. But hovering over it shows you the actual URL where you will be redirected upon clicking on it. When an email is formatted with HTML markup, one can include links in some string literals, where clicking on the links will redirect users to another website. 
The links could be deceiving, the text of the hyperlink could display www.bankofamerica.com, but the real hyperlink may lead to www.bankofarnerica.com – the letter “m” here is replaced by an r. Replacing characters is one of cyber criminals favorite techniques, so be extremely careful when clicking on links. Especially email links.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Attachments&lt;/b&gt; -  Whenever you receive an email from an unknown sender, and it contains an attachment, don’t click and download the attachment. Files with extension (files that end with) .zip, rar, .jpeg and .pdf are most commonly exploited by cyber criminals, as they provide different possibilities to infect a system – reverse shells, backdoors, and ransomware are just a fragment of the exploits you could end up infecting your system with.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Unusual Sender&lt;/b&gt; – Opening an email from an unknown sender can’t really hurt you. There isn’t anything that’s automatically downloaded (if you operate from a browser), and the email is just text, right? WRONG! By clicking on an email you can provide information such as: your IP address, your OS (Windows, Mac or Linux), your browser agent, the resolution of your screen, when exactly the email was opened, your time zone… See what I mean? By clicking on an email, you can provide cyber criminals with enough knowledge to have a basic footprint of your system and decide which attack vector to use next. Maybe they’ll try to compromise your network. Or your co-workers. Or use your siblings. Just opening an email could have devastating effects for an individual.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Back in the day when I was working at the Cybercrime Unit, I’ve utilized this technique many times in order to gather enough information, so that I could track down people who distributed child pornography and people sharing child nudity materials. I doubt that I’m using the word ‘people’ correctly here but nevertheless… Those sick bastards didn’t know who was sitting on the other side of the computer.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;So, we got the basics. Now what?&lt;b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;Everything you should know about phishing campaigns&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://onlinecorpus.com/everything-you-should-know-phishing-campaigns/&quot;&gt;In the next article&lt;/a&gt; we’re going to cover the ways a phishing campaign is being organized and executed.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>georgi</name></author><category term="cybercrime" /><category term="preventing" /><category term="phishing" /><category term="data" /><summary type="html">Phishing is without doubt the most commonly used and most preferred way to infiltrate any system. Perhaps you’ve heard of the phrase “You give a poor man a fish, and you feed him for a day, you teach him to phish, you give him… you give him…” – well the whole world actually.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/phishing-email-data-money.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/phishing-email-data-money.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Online Corpus - keep hackers away from your email inbox</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/online-corpus-mission/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Online Corpus - keep hackers away from your email inbox" /><published>2019-04-14T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2019-04-14T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/online-corpus-mission</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/online-corpus-mission/">&lt;h2 itemprop=&quot;articleSection&quot; class=&quot;h2-heading&quot;&gt;War against cyber criminals - Online Corpus key values&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ever wondered how people got as far as they are? Well, we did. 
The never-ending strive to know how things function the way they do made us discover very interesting things. Judging by how fast the world is changing, the next couple of decades will be one hell of a rollercoaster - technologically, politically and economically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But some things don’t change. As individuals, we have to satisfy different levels of needs in order to continue surviving and evolving - at least that’s what Abraham Maslow states.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The feeling of security several thousand years ago was something slightly different than now - back in the day people had no houses like us now, the only thing that they had was a tribe and some huts. And if we examine closely their habits, we will find a lot of differences with our current lifestyle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
As we evolve and progress technologically, mentally, and as a civilization, our needs change - now, for instance, it’s less possible that you’ll get hunted down by a predator or a foreign culture.&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;But the probability of someone stealing money from a bank account rises with the level of technical incompetence. Incompetence is a harsh word and implies that someone should feel guilty about something at a specific period of time. And that’s correct. When one’s knowledge is insufficient, a lot of problems could occur. But we can’t all be experts in every single field, can we?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fortunately for us, the 21.Century gives us strong computational power and a community of people, willing to help eachother for the sake of humanity itself.
&lt;p&gt;Our mission is to integrate an interoperable cross-platform security solution that will aid you in your day-to-day tasks.
&lt;p&gt;All round the world, businesses suffer under the hits of cunning cyber criminals - their corporate correspondence gets hacked, the lives of the people working at the company gets owned and, at the end, the company ends up being robbet at plain daylight by criminals, lurking in the shadows of the internet. 
&lt;p&gt;Anually, billions of dollars end up in Bank accounts of people all over the world, but mostly countries from the 'Eastern Block' of Europe - Bulgaria, Romania, Poland, Slovenia, Moldova, Czech Republic.
Despite all efforts, national legislation of some of those countries has not reached the minimal standard that can guarantee people's safety and well-being.
&lt;p&gt;This applies to companies as well.
&lt;p&gt;When a 'hacker' hijacks a company's online correspondence, the loss can be several tens of thousends of Euro. Big corporations can recover from such an attack, if it occurs, but the effect of some of the small businesses is almost always catastrophical. They cannot recover from such a loss. The psychological pressure on the owners and workers brings everyone to the edge of desparation, and often time causes severe emotinal crysis - the effects of which last for a long, long time.
&lt;p&gt;More and more malicious individuals decide to make their living not by contributing to the greater good of our global world, but rather attack and try to exploit non-suspcious small and middle-sized companies. In the last decade, this turned out to be one of the most profitable types of crimes.
&lt;p&gt;The main reason for this is that most companies neglect and completely ignore the need of an effective cyber security solution that can help them. Leaving their fate to the criminals and giving up the most valuable for every single individual, is the reason why more and more crimes of that nature occur. 
&lt;p&gt;The main reason why we decided to start Online Corpus is that in our experience as cyber crime investigators and security professionals, &lt;b&gt;THERE WAS NOT A SINGLE APPLICATION&lt;/b&gt; that could mitigate those kinds of attacks. 
Knowing the nature of the 'hackers', we knew what we should to in order to help the community. 
&lt;p&gt;We have spent years of researching and learning patterns of malicious individuals, thus we have come up with a great solution that can give you the tools that can help you keep all your money safe and sound, and your company - financially unharmed.
&lt;p&gt;Yet, 'hackers' are always on the move and in the lookout for new victims. 
That is where our tools can help you be one step ahead of them, and even if your correspondence gets compromised, you will be alerted.
&lt;p&gt;As every aspect of our live gets tightly coupeled with the Internet, and our online presence gains more and more significance, we have to come to the realization that cyber security tools and following best practices guidelines will be the things that guarantee our future well-being.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>ivan</name></author><category term="cybercrime" /><category term="onlinecorpus" /><summary type="html">War against cyber criminals - Online Corpus key values</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/cybercrime-hacking-income.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/posts/cybercrime-hacking-income.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>