<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Online Corpus</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2019 22:25:10 +0300</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2019 22:25:10 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.5</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>The mission of Online Corpus</title>
        <description>
&lt;h2 itemprop=&quot;articleSection&quot; class=&quot;h2-heading&quot;&gt;According to Europol cybercrime investigators, income from cybercrime and cybercrime related activities in some European countries, has surpassed the income from drug trafficking and drug distribution for 2018&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;span itemprop=&quot;image&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/ImageObject&quot; id=&quot;business-image&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid&quot; itemprop=&quot;url&quot; src=&quot;https://onlinecorpus.com/img/cybercrime-hacking-income.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cybercrime income picture&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;

Ever wondered how people got as far as they are? Well, we did. 
The never-ending strive to know how things function the way they do made us discover very interesting things. Judging by how fast the world is changing, the next couple of decades will be one hell of a rollercoaster - technologically, politically and economically.

But some things don’t change. As individuals, we have to satisfy different levels of needs in order to continue surviving and evolving - at least that’s what Abraham Maslow states.

The feeling of security several thousand years ago was something slightly different than now - back in the day people had no houses like us now, the only thing that they had was a tribe and some huts. And if we examine closely their habits, we will find a lot of differences with our current lifestyle.

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019/04/14/Who-are-we/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019/04/14/Who-are-we/</guid>
        
        <category>cybercrime</category>
        
        <category>onlinecorpus</category>
        
        
        <category>onlinecorpus</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
